In the last several videos, we've been talking about doing a kind of abstract
在最后几个视频中，我们一直在谈论做一种抽象
computation. Computing with elements like Bottom the Constants and Top. And, in this
计算。使用诸如Bottom、常量和Top等元素进行计算。而且，在这件事上，
video, we're going to start to generalize those ideas a little bit. And the first
视频中，我们将开始对这些想法进行一点推广。也是第一个
thing we're going to talk about, the first step towards that generalization, is to
我们将要讨论的事情，通向这个概括的第一步，是
talk about orderings of those values. First, I'd like to introduce a technical
谈谈这些值的排序。首先，我想介绍一项技术
term. These values that we compute within program analysis, things like Bottom, the
学期。我们在程序分析中计算的这些值，比如Bottom、
Constants and Top, these are called Abstract Values. And that's just to
常量和顶部，这些称为抽象值。这只是为了
distinguish them from the Concrete Values, so the Concrete Values are the actual
将它们与具体的值区分开来，因此具体的值就是实际的
run-time values that a program computes with. Things like actual objects, and
程序用来计算的运行时值。像实物一样的东西，还有
numbers and things like that. And the Abstract Values here the program analysis
数字之类的东西。以及这里的程序分析的抽象值
uses are in general, more abstract. Some particular Abstract Values can stand for a
用途一般都比较抽象。某些特定的抽象值可以表示
set of possible Concrete Values. And in a particular set of Abstract Values we're
一组可能的具体值。在一组特定的抽象值中，我们
using for concept propagation, there's only one very Abstract Value and that's
用于概念传播，只有一个非常抽象的值，那就是
the Top and it stands for any possible run time value. So it stands for the entire
Top，它代表任何可能的运行时值。所以它代表了整个
set of run time values. Anyway, it turns out that there is a way to simplify the
一组运行时值。无论如何，事实证明，有一种方法可以简化
presentation of, of the analysis that we have been discussing by ordering the
我们一直在讨论的分析的演示文稿，方法是订购
Abstract Values. So we're going to say is that Bottom is less than all the constants
抽象值。所以我们要说的是底部小于所有常量
and that, and all the Constants are less than Top. And so if we draw a picture with
然后，所有的常数都小于Top。所以如果我们画一幅画
the lower values drawn towards at the bottom picture and the higher values drawn
在底图中绘制的值越小，绘制的值越高
at the top. And, and edges between values where there's a relationship, we get this
在顶端。并且，在有关系的值之间的边缘，我们得到这个
diagram here. So you have bottom down here, underneath all the other values,
图在这里。所以你在这里有底部，在所有其他值的下面，
Bottom is less than every Constant. Okay. So notice that all the constants are here
底部小于每个常数。好吧。请注意，所有常量都在这里
on the middle level, alright? And also notice that the constants are not
在中层，好吗？还要注意，常量不是
comparable to each other, alright? So this ordering is different than the numeric
互相比较，好吗？因此，此顺序不同于数字
ordering. So zero is not less than one for example. Zero and one are inco mparable,
点菜。例如，0不小于1。0和1是不可比拟的，
as are every other pair of Constants. So you have, you know, Bottom at the Bottom.
其他每对常量也是如此。所以你有，你知道，在底部。
You have all the Constants in the middle and they're incomparable, And then, bigger
你把所有的常数都放在中间，它们是无与伦比的，然后更大
than everything else is Top. Now with the ordering defined, there's a useful
比其他一切都要好。现在定义了顺序后，有一个有用的
operation we can define on collections of elements and that is the Least Upper
我们可以在元素集合上定义的运算，那就是最小上限
Bound, or LUB, alright? And, and this means is taking the smallest element that
捆绑，还是卢布，好吗？这就是说，取最小的元素，
is bigger than everything in the Least Upper Bound. So, for example, if I have
比最小上界中的一切都要大。所以，举个例子，如果我有
the Least Upper Bound of Bottom and one, that is equal to one, okay? If I had the
下限和1的最小上界等于1，好吗？如果我有
Least Upper Bound of Top and Bottom, that is equal to Top. And perhaps more
顶部和底部的最小上限，即等于顶部。也许还有更多
interesting one, the Least Upper Bound of one and two, so two incomparable Constants
有趣的一个，1和2的最小上界，所以两个不可比较的常数
here. And remember, the meaning of the Least Upper Bound, it's the smallest
这里。记住，最小上限的意思是，它是最小的
element in the ordering that's bigger than everything over which we're taking the
元素，该元素比我们要处理的所有内容都要大。
Least Upper Bound. So we just have two things here in our Least Upper Bound. But
最小上界。所以我们这里只有两样东西在我们的最小上界。但
the Least Upper Bound of one and two, the smallest thing that's bigger than both of
1和2的最小上界，比两者都大的最小的东西
them, or greater than or equal I should say, both of them is Top, okay? And so,
他们，或者大于或者等于，我应该说，他们两个都是最好的，好吗？因此，
the Least Upper Bound then, if you think about it, if you draw, draw our picture
最小上界那么，如果你想一想，如果你画，画我们的画
again. So we had Bottom and we had Top, and if you pick out some points here,
再来一次。所以我们有底部，我们有顶部，如果你在这里挑出一些点，
let's say we want to take the Least Upper Bound of Bottom and two, you're just
比方说我们要取最小上界的底数和2，你只是
picking the smallest thing that's bigger than both. Well, that's going to be two
选择比两者都大的最小的东西。嗯，那将是两个
itself, similarly two on Top, you will get Top. And then if have anything that's
本身，同样两个在上面，你会得到第一。如果有什么是
incomparable, then you have to pick something that's bigger than both of them
无与伦比的，那你就得选比这两个都大的
and in this case that will always end up being Top for this very simple ordering,
在这种情况下，对于这个非常简单的排序，它最终将始终是最高的，
alright? Then given this idea of the Least Upper Bound, it turns out that rules one
好吗？然后给出这个最小上界的想法，结果是规则之一
through four, all they're doing is computing the Least Upper Bound. So the in
到了4点，他们所做的就是计算最小上界。所以在这里
of a statement is just equal to the Least Upper Bound of the out of all the
语句的最小上界恰好等于所有
predecessors. Alright, and that's all that rules one through four we're saying. And
前辈。好的，这就是我们所说的第一条到第四条规则。和
if you remember what we had there, we had, you know, we had a bunch of predecessors
如果你记得我们在那里有什么，我们有，你知道，我们有一堆前辈
and then there's some kind of statement s, and all we're doing is whatever the
然后是某种声明s，我们所做的就是
information is on these predecessors, we're just taking the Least Upper Bound
信息是关于这些前身的，我们只是取了最小的上界
over it, all right? And that is the information on entry to, to s. The
越过它，好吗？这是关于进入s，到s的信息。
ordering on the Abstract Values also helps to clarify another important aspect of our
对抽象值进行排序还有助于阐明我们的
analysis algorithm which is why it terminates. So remember the algorithm's
分析算法，这就是它终止的原因。所以请记住算法的
termination condition is to repeat to repeatedly apply the rules until nothing
终止条件是重复应用规则，直到什么都没有
changes, until there are no more inconsistencies in the control flow graph
更改，直到控制流图中不再有不一致为止。
and there's no information left to update. Well, just because we say we're going to
而且也没有什么信息可以更新了。嗯，不能因为我们说我们要
repeat until nothing changes, that doesn't guarantee that eventually nothing changes.
重复这一过程，直到什么都没有改变，这并不能保证最终什么都没有改变。
It could be that, that goes on forever, that we always introduce new
这可能是因为，这将永远持续下去，我们总是引入新的
inconsistencies with every update and we never actually get to the point where all
每一次更新都不一致，我们实际上从未达到这样的地步
the information is consistent. So, the ordering actually shows why that can't
这些信息是一致的。所以，排序实际上说明了为什么它不能
happen and the algorithm is guaranteed to terminate. So remember that in every
并且保证算法终止。所以请记住，在每一个
program point except the entry point, the values start as Bottom. So, they start at
程序点除入口点外，值从底部开始。所以，他们的起步价是
the lowest place in the ordering. And then if you look carefully at the rules, it's
排序最低的位置。如果你仔细看规则，就会发现
easy to see that the rules can only make the values increase at a program point. So
很容易看出，规则只能使值在程序点增加。所以
Bottom can be promoted, can be changed at a given program point up to some Constant
底部可以提升，可以在给定的程序点改变到某个常量
and, and, and another update could raise that Constant to Top but of course, once
并且，并且，另一次更新可以将该常量提高到Top，但当然，一次
we get the Top, there's no greater element. And if the rules can only make
我们得到了顶峰，没有比这更好的元素了。如果规则只能让
the elements increase, then eventually we have to run out of elements that could be
元素增加，那么最终我们必须耗尽可能是
increased, okay? So what that says is that each piece of information we're computing,
增加了，好吗？这就是说，我们正在计算的每一条信息，
for every statement, for every variable, and for either in or out, it can change at
对于每个语句、每个变量以及In或Out，它都可以在
most twice, okay? So it can go from a Bottom to a Constant, and from Constant to
最多两次，好吗？所以它可以从底部到常数，从常数到
a Top but after that, it will never be updated again. And what this means is that
A顶部，但在那之后，它就再也不会更新了。这意味着
the constant propagation algorithm that we've described is actually linear in
我们描述的常量传播算法实际上是线性的
program size. So the number of steps is gonna be bounded by the number of c values
程序大小。所以步数将由c值的个数来限定
that we're trying to compute times two, cuz each one of those could change two
我们要计算的是2倍，因为每一次都可以改变2次
times. And since there's one value for the entry and exit over the in and out of
泰晤士报。由于入口和出口与进出之间只有一个值
every statement, the total number of steps that the algorithm can possibly take is
每条语句中，算法可能采取的步骤总数为
the number of program statements times four.
程序语句的数量乘以4。